<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deeplearning4j on cmhh</title>
    <link>/tags/deeplearning4j/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deeplearning4j on cmhh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/deeplearning4j/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Learning with Akka</title>
      <link>/2021/2021-08-08-online-learning-with-akka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/2021-08-08-online-learning-with-akka/</guid>
      <description>Overview In a previous post, we looked at how we could consume messages in a Kafka topic, and use those messages for online training of a classifier. In this post, we look at how Akka could be used to solve the same problem, in broadly the same way. Akka is an implementation of the actor model, and is particularly well suited for building event-driven, reactive systems since the actors involved communicate exclusively by sending and reacting to messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Learning with Apache Kafka</title>
      <link>/2021/2021-07-30-online-learning-with-apache-kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/2021-07-30-online-learning-with-apache-kafka/</guid>
      <description>Overview I recently came across a scenario at work that would, like so many things in practice, be particularly well modelled as an ordered set of events. The messages would have a large number of uses in practice, but one would involve using them to train some sort of predictive model. Moreover, the messages would be arriving in real-time, and the patterns underpinning the messages might well change over time. Based on previous research, Kafka seemed like it would be a good fit, though I don&amp;rsquo;t yet have a huge amount of practical experience using it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
